[
    {
        "question": "1. Compare QlikView with Tableau.",
        "answer": "Criteria Tableau QlikView\nPerformance Uses a cubing technique that gives out results slower than QlikView Faster than Tableau as it effortlessly combines all sizes of datasets\nInterface Comes up with a simple drag-and-drop interface that is easy, clean, and interactive Has too many tools that are rarely used but certainly provide numerous ways for showcasing data\nSuitable for Provides dashboarding and rapid visualization Offers departmental and enterprise-wide BI solutions\nProduct range Has diverse products for varied uses Has a single product for the entire BI solutions\nGeographical maps Building map visualization is easy with its in-built extension Building map visualization takes longer since it needs scripting and an external extension for this\nTables Weaker for tables Very good for tables\nSpeed Depends on RAM and the source database Depends on RAM\nGraphical inputs and changes With easy drag and drop, graphical inputs are easy For graphical changes, we will have to write the logic for it",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What chart types do we use in QlikView Admin?",
        "answer": "In QlikView Admin, we generally use bar charts, line charts, combo charts, scatter charts, grid charts, etc.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. Explain Set Analysis in QlikView.",
        "answer": "Mostly used in aggregated functions like sum (year), avg, max, min, etc., set analysis is used to define a set (or a group) of data values.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. Define Trellis chart.",
        "answer": "In the trellis chart, we can create an array of charts based on the first dimension. It is basically a grid of small charts or a repetition of charts. Bitmap charts can also be made up of the trellis display.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. Explain Mini chart. What do you mean by sub-reports and how can you create them?",
        "answer": "In QlikView, with the help of a mini chart, we can set the type of modes, instead of values, in the table mode. We can also set colors for the chart.\nRead this QlikView Tutorial to learn more about QlikView now!\nGet 100% Hike!\nMaster Most in Demand Skills Now !\nBy providing your contact details, you agree to our Terms of Use & Privacy Policy",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. What is a Pivot table?",
        "answer": "A pivot table is better at the time of grouping. We can also show a pivot table like a cross table, which is a beneficial feature. However, there is a disadvantage with pivot tables, i.e., if we have to sort a pivot table, then we have to sort it first according to the first dimension, then to the next.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. Which graph can you use for 2 years' difference sales?",
        "answer": "A bar graph can be used for this purpose.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What is a Straight table?",
        "answer": "A straight table is much better at the time of sorting when compared to the pivot table as we can sort the former according to any column as per our choice. However, it is not good for the grouping purpose.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. How many dimensions can you use in a Bar chart?",
        "answer": "In a bar chart, we can use only two dimensions.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. Which QlikView object has only expression and no dimension?",
        "answer": "Gauge chart and list box have only expression and no dimension.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. How can you use Macros in your application?",
        "answer": "We can use macros for various purposes, such as reloading the application and creating an object.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. What do you understand by layers in QlikView?",
        "answer": "Layers are basically set on sheet object properties in the layout tab, where there are options such as Bottom, Top, and Normal, respective to the numbers −1, 0, and 1.\nLearn How QlikView is used as a BI tool and about its strengths, from this informative blog!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. What are Dimensions?",
        "answer": "Dimensions allow data examination from various perspectives.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. Explain Normalized data.",
        "answer": "Normalized data: By saying normalized data, we mean the well-structured form of data, which doesn’t have any repetition or redundancy. It is a kind of relational data mainly used in OLTP-like stuff.\nDenormalized data: Along with normalized data, we have denormalized data as well. It is a whole bunch of data without any relationship among themselves, with the possibility of redundancy. It’s mainly used in OLAP-like stuff.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. What is Star Schema?",
        "answer": "Star schema is the simplest form of a dimensional model, in which data is pre-arranged into facts and dimensions.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. What is Snowflake Schema?",
        "answer": "A snowflake schema is a different form of the star schema. A snowflake schema is used to improve the presentation of particular queries.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "17. Explain IntervalMatch.",
        "answer": "IntervalMatch prefixes with the load statement that is used for connecting different numeric values to one or more numeric intervals.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "18. Explain the IntervalMatch() function.",
        "answer": "The IntervalMatch() function is used to generate data buckets of different sizes.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "19. What is a Container?",
        "answer": "A container object is used to keep multiple charts. We can use a container object to keep many charts in the same box.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "20. What do you understand by the extended IntervalMatch() function?",
        "answer": "The extended IntervalMatch() function is used for Slowly Changing Dimensions.\nAre you interested in learning QlikView? Well, we have the top QlikView Training Course to give you a head start in your career!\n\nIntermediate QlikView Interview Questions and Answers",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "21. What are the new features in QV 11?",
        "answer": "Container object, granular chart dimension control, actions like clear filed, metadata, etc. are some of the new features in QV 11.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "22. Explain Join and its types.",
        "answer": "Join is used to convert the given data, and whenever we use joins for converting data it is known as data merging.\nIt has many types:\na. Left join\nb. Right join\nc. Inner join, etc.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "23. What is Left Join?",
        "answer": "Left join specifies that the join between two tables should be left join; it uses before the word ‘join’. The resulting table only contains the combination among two tables with the full dataset from the first table. When we have more than one common field between two or more tables, then we have synthetic keys.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "24. Define Right Join.",
        "answer": "Right join specifies that the join between the two tables should be right join; it uses before the word ‘join’. The resulting table only contains the combination among two tables with the full dataset from the second table.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "25. Explain Inner Join.",
        "answer": "Inner join specifies that the join between the two tables should be inner join. The resulting table should contain the full dataset from both tables.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "26. What are Modifiers?",
        "answer": "Modifiers deal with the Fields name.\nExample:\nsum({$<Region=>}Sales)\nThe above code returns the sales for the current selection, but the selection in ‘Region’ is removed.\nGo through this insightful blog to learn Why QlikView is such a great Business Intelligence tool?!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "27. Explain Identifier's syntax.",
        "answer": "0: Represents an empty set\n1: Represents full sets of records\n$: Represents the record of the current selection\n$1: Represents the previous selection\n$_1: Represents the next selection\nBookmark01: Represents the Bookmark name",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "28. Explain the 3-tier architecture of QlikView Application.",
        "answer": "Tier I: Raw data is loaded, and QVD is created\nTier II: QVD is converted in business login and the requirement of business and data model is created.\nTier III: Reading all QVD from Tier II, a single QVW is made.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "29. How does QlikView store data internally?",
        "answer": "QlikView stores data in QVD as QVD has data compression capability. QlikView has better performance than other BI tools because of its memory analytics approach.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "30. Explain the restrictions of Binary Load for a QlikView Developer.",
        "answer": "Binary Load can be used only for one application, i.e., we can only read data from one QVW application. Moreover, set scripts is also a restriction.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "31. For a QlikView Administrator, differentiate between Subset Ratio and Information Density.",
        "answer": "Subset Ratio: It is used for easily spotting problems in the key field association. It is only relevant for key fields as they are present in multiple tables and do not share the same value.\nInformation Density: It is the field that contains the percentage of rows with non-null values.\nInterested in learning QlikView? Grab our online QlikView Administrator Training Course!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "32. What is the use of Optimized Load?",
        "answer": "Optimized load is much faster and preferable especially for large sets of data. It is possible if no transformation is made at the time of load and no filtering is done.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "33. Differentiate between Keep and Join.",
        "answer": "Keep and Join do the same functions, but keep creates two tables whereas join merges two tables to create one table. Keep is used before the load or select statement.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "34. Define Synthetic Key.",
        "answer": "A synthetic key is the key used when two or more tables consist of more than one common column among them.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "35. What is Incremental Load in QlikView Architect?",
        "answer": "Incremental load is nothing but loading new or changed records from the database. With the help of QVD files, we can use incremental load.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "36. Differentiate between the Set and Let options in QlikView.",
        "answer": "Set: It assigns a variable to a value without assessing the expression.\nLet: It assigns a variable to a value after assessing the expression.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "37. Define QlikView Resident Load.",
        "answer": "Resident load is a part of loading data in the QlikView application. It is used for loading the data in tables, which is already loaded in the Qlikview application.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "38. How can you optimize a QV Application?",
        "answer": "A QV application can be optimized by creating QVDs for data. When the complete QVW application is changed into a QVD, then this QVD will be stored in the RAM.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "39. What is Mapping Load?",
        "answer": "Mapping load is used to create the mapping table that can be used for replacing field values and field names.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "40. Define Apply Map.",
        "answer": "Apply map is used to add fields to tables with the help of other tables. It can be used as a join.\nGive your career a big boost by taking up our QlikView Training now!\n\nAdvanced QlikView Interview Questions and Answers for Experienced",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "41. What is Concatenation?",
        "answer": "Concatenation means a sequence of interconnected things, i.e., any columns or rows that are related to each other can be connected through concatenation.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "42. Define NoConcatenation.",
        "answer": "NoConcatenation prefix is used to force two identical tables as two separate internal tables.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "43. Define the Connect statement.",
        "answer": "The connect statement is used to establish a connection to the database with the help of an ODBC or an OLEDB interface.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "44. What do you understand by Fact Constellation Schema?",
        "answer": "Fact Constellation schema is a logical database structure of a data warehouse. It is designed with the help of a denormalized fact.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "45. What do you mean by RDBMS?",
        "answer": "RDBMS stands for ‘Relational Database Management System.’ It arranges data into respective columns and rows.\nHave more queries? Clear all your doubts by sharing them on our BI Community and get them clarified within a day!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "46. What do you understand by the term 'CAL' in QlikView Server?",
        "answer": "Every client needs a CAL to get connected with Qlikview Server. CALS are taken up with QlikView Server and tied up with the server serial number.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "47. Differentiate between QlikView Server and QlikView Publisher.",
        "answer": "QlikView Server is a program that is installed on a computer with various CALS allowing users to access the QV files on the server.\nQlikView Publisher is a program that has centralized control on our QV files and manages how and when they are loaded and distributed.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "48. What do you understand by the Snapshot View of a table?",
        "answer": "By this option, we can see a number of tables and related associations.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "49. How can you bring data into QV?",
        "answer": "We can use ODBC, OLEDB, or SAP connectors as a kind of data connection.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "50. How can you handle Early Arriving Facts?",
        "answer": "We can load data from ODBC, OLEDB, or SAP connectors with the help of the select statement, and we can load files like Excel, Word, etc. by using the table syntax.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "51. What type of data do we use generally?",
        "answer": "We use flat files, Excel files, QVDs, etc. as data.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "52. Elucidate QlikView.",
        "answer": "QlikView is the Business Intelligence tool used by the University of St Andrews. With QlikView, data from different university systems are combined and presented in a single dashboard in an easy and understandable way.\nQlikView dashboards at the University of St Andrews are built on the following principles:\nDashboards must be effective to use.\nDashboards must support users in carrying out their tasks.\nDashboards must provide the right kind of functionality.\nIt should be easy to learn and remember how to use a dashboard.\nTo use QlikView, users need not have any technical expertise in information systems, but a willingness to learn would be good to have.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "53. What are the benefits of using QlikView?",
        "answer": "As the name suggests, QlikView is a combination of ‘quick’ and ‘click,’ and its features make it intuitive and easy to use. Users can visualize data, search in multiple datasets, create ad-hoc reports, and view patterns and trends in data that may not be visible in other reports.\nQlikView is:\nFlexible: Dashboards are web-based and accessible from desktop computers and mobile devices.\nInteractive: Users are able to easily drill down and select particular data from charts or tables.\nUsable: Users can see large amounts of data effectively and efficiently.\nScalable: QlikView is useful for multiple business processes at analytical, operational, and strategic levels.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "54. How is QlikView 11 different from QlikView 10?",
        "answer": "QlikView 11 brings new levels of capabilities and manageability to the QlikView Business Discovery platform. In this release, it has focused its investments on five value propositions:\nImprove collaborative decision-making with Social Business Discovery\nGain new insights into opportunities and threats and relative business performance with comparative analysis\nExpand QlikView usage to additional devices, including smartphones, with mobile Business Discovery\nEnable a broad spectrum of users to jointly develop QlikView apps with QlikView’s rapid analytic app platform capabilities\nImprove the manageability and performance of QlikView with new enterprise platform capabilities\nMaster QlikView with the latest version of Intellipaat’s QlikView Certification Training!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "55. What is QlikView Comparative Analysis in the QlikView Developer platform?",
        "answer": "Business users can quickly gain new insights when analyzing their information in QlikView, with its new comparative analysis options. QlikView app developers can now create multiple selection states in a QlikView app; they can create graphs, tables, or sheets based on different selection sets.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "56. What mobile device platforms does QlikView 11 support?",
        "answer": "QlikView 11 delivers mobile functionality for Apple iOS and Android tablets and smartphones. QlikView supports Android tablets when the following conditions are met:\nQlikView Server 10 SR3 or later versions\nA native browser, not a downloaded one\nCurrently, HTML5 web apps support only Apple and Android handhelds because BlackBerry devices are older that do not fully support HTML5 (and many of them are having non-touch screens). QlikView doesn’t have a web-based solution for them as of now.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "57. For a QlikView Admin, what is Document-level Auditing in QlikView 11?",
        "answer": "New optional settings within QlikView Management Console enable administrators to more effectively audit user interactions. Administrators can now audit QlikView usage not only at the system level (the entire QlikView Server) but down to the document level as well.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "58. What are the key differences between QlikView and any other standard statistical software packages (SAS, SPSS, etc.)?",
        "answer": "The key difference is in terms of the database used. While SAS is useful in the case of metadata and SPSS is good for analysis; QlikView offers quite a simple visualization that matches MS Excel filtering.\nWhen comparing QlikView with the other two, it is the most user-friendly and the fastest in terms of generating diverse dashboards/templates.\nIn terms of calculations, advanced statistics options are limited in QlikView.\nFor market research and analysis, SPSS has direct facility algorithms.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "59. What are QlikView Annotations?",
        "answer": "With the new annotations collaboration object, QlikView users can engage in threaded discussions with the QlikView content. A user can create notes associated with any QlikView object. Other users can then add their own commentary to create a threaded discussion.\nUsers can capture snapshots of their selections and include them in the discussion so that others can get back to the same place in the analysis when reviewing notes and comments. Also, QlikView captures the state of the object (current selections), as well as knows who has made each note and comment and when and how a decision was made.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "60. What are the main features of QlikView?",
        "answer": "QlikView offers the following features:\nDynamic BI ecosystem\nData visualization\nInteractivity with dynamic apps, dashboards, and analytics\nSearch across the entire data\nSecure and real-time collaboration",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. What are the essential QlikView features?",
        "answer": "QlikView has many features that help you quickly create advanced reports from multiple data sources. Below are some of the features that make QlikView unique: Natural analytics and data discovery: QlikView searches through all the data stored in the memory in a natural manner. Natural search means that the data searching process does not follow predefined patterns, but instead will search for data and associations in a way that is the most natural. Within QlikView apps, users can quickly discover and analyze data.\nData collaboration and connectivity: Qlik DataMarket (DaaS) is a unique QlikView cloud-based data service that allows users to fetch data sets from different syndicated and public data sources. Several public datasets are available, including population, currencies, business demographics, weather conditions, economic indicators, etc. RESTful API connectors can also be used to connect and integrate with data sources like Facebook, Alfresco, Twitter, LinkedIn, Adobe, Documentum, etc.\nData association is automatically maintained: QlikView recognizes or identifies the relationship between every piece of data in a dataset automatically. Therefore, users do not have to pre-configure relationships between data entities.\nIn-memory storage capability: In-memory storage technology is one of QlikView's key strengths. Data from different sources (including traditional sources like data warehouses) are loaded or stored into RAM on the system and can later be retrieved directly from there.\nAssociative model: QlikView is the only tool that offers an associative data discovery model. It simplifies the process of discovering and analyzing data in BI tools. As a result of these associations, we create a logical connection by linking related data fields and data values with each other.\nComparative Analysis: Comparative analysis in QlikView is an extension of the associative model. Comparisons of different fields and data sets are possible through comparative analysis. Users and developers can choose which data sections or states to compare. The comparison of data is aided by charts, tables, and graphs for better understanding and analysis. Natural analytics and data discovery: QlikView searches through all the data stored in the memory in a natural manner. Natural search means that the data searching process does not follow predefined patterns, but instead will search for data and associations in a way that is the most natural. Within QlikView apps, users can quickly discover and analyze data. Natural analytics and data discovery Data collaboration and connectivity: Qlik DataMarket (DaaS) is a unique QlikView cloud-based data service that allows users to fetch data sets from different syndicated and public data sources. Several public datasets are available, including population, currencies, business demographics, weather conditions, economic indicators, etc. RESTful API connectors can also be used to connect and integrate with data sources like Facebook, Alfresco, Twitter, LinkedIn, Adobe, Documentum, etc. Data collaboration and connectivity Data association is automatically maintained: QlikView recognizes or identifies the relationship between every piece of data in a dataset automatically. Therefore, users do not have to pre-configure relationships between data entities. Data association is automatically maintained In-memory storage capability: In-memory storage technology is one of QlikView's key strengths. Data from different sources (including traditional sources like data warehouses) are loaded or stored into RAM on the system and can later be retrieved directly from there. In-memory storage capability: Associative model: QlikView is the only tool that offers an associative data discovery model. It simplifies the process of discovering and analyzing data in BI tools. As a result of these associations, we create a logical connection by linking related data fields and data values with each other. Associative model: Comparative Analysis: Comparative analysis in QlikView is an extension of the associative model. Comparisons of different fields and data sets are possible through comparative analysis. Users and developers can choose which data sections or states to compare. The comparison of data is aided by charts, tables, and graphs for better understanding and analysis. Comparative Analysis:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. With the Tools menu provided in QlikView's Menu bar, what operations can be performed?",
        "answer": "From the Tools menu, we can choose the Edit menu to edit the tools, and create different kinds of charts with wizards such as the Time Chart Wizard, Quick Chart Wizard, Box Plot Wizard, and Statistics Chart Wizard. Alerts and themes can also be managed using this tool menu.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. Describe Inline data. Is there a way to load Inline into QlikView?",
        "answer": "You can directly enter the data into a QlikView document by typing it in or pasting it in. This is known as inline data. Data can be loaded into QlikView quickly via the clipboard. You can access this feature from the Insert tab of the script editor. As shown below, open up the script editor, and then go to and click on Insert –> Load Statement –> Load Inline option.   As soon as we open the screen above, we see a spreadsheet-like document as shown below where values can be typed. The column headers are generated automatically.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. Is it possible to import or load Web files into QlikView?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can load web files into QlikView using the Script Editor. For connecting to and retrieving data from different data sources, QlikView uses load scripts, which can be managed within the script editor.  The file is loaded into QlikView via the load script, which can be seen in the below screenshot. So, if we use a delimited file, we can tweak/modify the below-given script as required.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What do you mean by delimited files? And why are they called CSV files?",
        "answer": "QlikView delimited files are text files in which the data fields are separated using commas, semicolons, tabs, etc. These types of files are also known as CSVs (comma-separated values) and have the extension '.csv'. CSV files can be loaded in QlikView. They are useful since they allow storing large amounts of data in a simple text format.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. In QlikView, which types of data files can be loaded?",
        "answer": "In QlikView, there are several types of QlikView data files available from which data can be loaded. Listed below are a few of them: Delimited Files: Store large amounts of data in a simple text format.\nFixed Record Files: Consist of data records or rows that have the same length or byte size.\nDif Files (Data Interchange Format files): Used for importing and exporting spreadsheet data. They only contain data from one spreadsheet. \nExcel (XLS) Files: Contain data created in MS Excel documents.\nExcel (XLSX) Files: Use for storing data from MS Excel documents.\nHTML (HyperText Markup Language) Files: Also known as web files, and contains information on a web page.\nQVD (QlikView Data) Files: A file that can be used to read and write data to and from QlikView. Files like these are mainly used by QlikView services as storage and as intermediate files.\nKML Files (Keyhole Markup Language): A file format for defining and storing geographic data used in earth browsers. Delimited Files: Store large amounts of data in a simple text format. Delimited Files Fixed Record Files: Consist of data records or rows that have the same length or byte size. Fixed Record Files Dif Files (Data Interchange Format files): Used for importing and exporting spreadsheet data. They only contain data from one spreadsheet. Dif Files (Data Interchange Format files) Excel (XLS) Files: Contain data created in MS Excel documents. Excel (XLS) Files Excel (XLSX) Files: Use for storing data from MS Excel documents. Excel (XLSX) Files: HTML (HyperText Markup Language) Files: Also known as web files, and contains information on a web page. HTML (HyperText Markup Language) Files: QVD (QlikView Data) Files: A file that can be used to read and write data to and from QlikView. Files like these are mainly used by QlikView services as storage and as intermediate files. QVD (QlikView Data) Files KML Files (Keyhole Markup Language): A file format for defining and storing geographic data used in earth browsers. KML Files (Keyhole Markup Language):",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. Can you tell me how to use macros in an application?",
        "answer": "A Qlik macro is generally a set of tasks that you want to automate - for reporting purposes, these tasks would otherwise need to be done manually. This concept is similar to Excel macros. Macros can be used for the following things: To reload an application.\nAs well as to create objects. To reload an application. As well as to create objects.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. Explain the fact constellation schema.",
        "answer": "A fact constellation schema is basically a way to represent a multidimensional model. This model includes several fact tables which share some common dimension tables. It can be considered a collection of multiple star schemas and is therefore also known as a galaxy schema.   In the above diagram, yellow-coloured Dimension tables are the ones common to both star schemas. The blue-coloured fact tables correspond to their respective star schemas.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. Explain aggregate functions.",
        "answer": "In QlikView, you can bundle or aggregate data from rows within a table by using the Aggregate function. This function lets you apply mathematical or statistical operations on large data chunks collectively. There are different types of aggregate functions in QlikView, each based on the actions they take on the data as shown below:  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. What is a previous function in QlikView?",
        "answer": "A previous() function finds or determines the value of the ‘expr’ expression utilizing the data from the previous input record that hasn't been discarded due to a where clause. The function will return NULL in the first row of an internal table. expr Syntax: Previous(expr) Previous(expr) Here, expr is the expression that contains the data to be measured.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. Explain QlikView Dashboard.",
        "answer": "QlikView Dashboards are essentially sheets or documents that contain various sheet objects containing the loaded data in the QlikView script. In a dashboard, values from various fields are displayed simultaneously. A dashboard allows users to view and analyze data in several ways and with different types of sheet objects.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. What is a container?",
        "answer": "In QlikView, there is an object called CONTAINER that allows multiple chart objects to be displayed at once that can be accessed through tabs. In the container, multiple charts are housed in the same box, as shown below. You will see all charts in the same window, but only one will be active at a time, and you can navigate between charts using the bottom tabs. Tab positions can be changed to top, left, or right as well. Example: Look at the following snapshot. There are four different charts in one container, including Region-wise sales, Manpower distribution, Region-wise profit, and YoY growth. These charts can be accessed by clicking on their respective tabs. Example:  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. What do you mean by applymap() in Qlik sense?",
        "answer": "Using the ApplyMap() script function, you can map an expression's output to a previously loaded mapping table. Syntax: Syntax: ApplyMap('map_name', expression [ , default_mapping ] ) ApplyMap('map_name', expression [ , default_mapping ] ) Here, map_name: Name of a mapping table that has been created by a load or a select statement.\nexpression: The expression refers to the piece of the quote or the condition, whose result should be mapped.\ndefault_mapping: If the mapping table does not contain a matching value for an expression, this value is used as the default mapping value. map_name: Name of a mapping table that has been created by a load or a select statement. map_name: expression: The expression refers to the piece of the quote or the condition, whose result should be mapped. expression: default_mapping: If the mapping table does not contain a matching value for an expression, this value is used as the default mapping value. default_mapping",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. What is mapping load in QlikView?",
        "answer": "In QlikView, you can use the Mapping Load statement to load data fields and values (from pre-existing tables from various sources and models) into a newly created mapping table. These are temporary tables as they are automatically removed from the data model at the end of the script execution.\n\nSyntax:   Syntax: Mapping (loadstatement | selectstatement) Mapping (loadstatement | selectstatement) Here, the prefix 'Mapping' is used to LOAD/SELECT statements that instruct or command the system to save the loaded fields in a mapping table.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. What are the different types of loads in QlikView?",
        "answer": "There are different methods or ways to load data into QlikView. Listed below are a few of them: Data loading from file: It is a normal method used to load data into the Qlikview application.  Data can be loaded from different types of files, including Excel, CSV, Text files, etc. You can achieve this by creating ODBC (Open Database Connectivity) and OLEDB (Object Linking and Embedding Database) as well as connecting directly to your database.\nInline load: An inline load is another way to load data, which allows the user to define their own data and load it within Qlikview. It is possible to define Inline Data in the Inline Data Wizard.\nIncremental load: Incremental load in QlikView is used to load only newly added or changed records instead of the entire dataset every day. It will come in handy when a database is large.\nBuffer load: Buffer load in QlikView helps to create and maintain the QVD (QlikView Data) files automatically. Data loading from file: It is a normal method used to load data into the Qlikview application.  Data can be loaded from different types of files, including Excel, CSV, Text files, etc. You can achieve this by creating ODBC (Open Database Connectivity) and OLEDB (Object Linking and Embedding Database) as well as connecting directly to your database. Data loading from file: Inline load: An inline load is another way to load data, which allows the user to define their own data and load it within Qlikview. It is possible to define Inline Data in the Inline Data Wizard. Inline load: Incremental load: Incremental load in QlikView is used to load only newly added or changed records instead of the entire dataset every day. It will come in handy when a database is large. Incremental load: Buffer load: Buffer load in QlikView helps to create and maintain the QVD (QlikView Data) files automatically. Buffer load:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. State difference between QlikView vs Qlik Sense.",
        "answer": "QlikView and Qlik Sense are the main products offered by the Qlik software company. Both QlikView and Qlik Sense are BI tools and have many similarities, but each is tailored to a particular market and serves a different purpose. QlikView  Qlik Sense\nQlikView is a business intelligence tool that is widely used to provide analytical solutions, data visualization, and insight for business growth and monitoring. It is a version of QlikView, launched in 2014, with some advanced features. It helps in building interactive dashboards and reports and also extracting data from various data sources.\nWith QlikView, you can perform analytical operations on data through Online Analytical Processing (OLAP). There is no OLAP functionality in Qlik Sense.\nQlikView does not support self-service visualization. Data mining and analytics are not available either. Qlik Sense supports self-service visualization. Data mining and analytics are also included.\nIt does provide guided analytics functionality. It does not provide guided analytics functionality.\nQlikView provides basic visualizations. The attractive interface of Qlik Sense makes it a favourite among consumers. Therefore, Qlik Sense provides modern visualizations for representing data along with simple drag-and-drop functionality.\nThe tool is used by technical users since it is required to manipulate data via scripting. Furthermore, it can also be used by non-technical users.\nThere are no AI-enabled insights (Artificial Intelligence) or chart suggestions in QlikView. Additionally, Qlik Sense provides AI-enabled insights and chart suggestions.\nAdditionally, it enables us to integrate data from multiple sources and visualize those data. We can use it for data monitoring, security, application management, data auditing, data connectivity, and task management. QlikView  Qlik Sense\nQlikView is a business intelligence tool that is widely used to provide analytical solutions, data visualization, and insight for business growth and monitoring. It is a version of QlikView, launched in 2014, with some advanced features. It helps in building interactive dashboards and reports and also extracting data from various data sources.\nWith QlikView, you can perform analytical operations on data through Online Analytical Processing (OLAP). There is no OLAP functionality in Qlik Sense.\nQlikView does not support self-service visualization. Data mining and analytics are not available either. Qlik Sense supports self-service visualization. Data mining and analytics are also included.\nIt does provide guided analytics functionality. It does not provide guided analytics functionality.\nQlikView provides basic visualizations. The attractive interface of Qlik Sense makes it a favourite among consumers. Therefore, Qlik Sense provides modern visualizations for representing data along with simple drag-and-drop functionality.\nThe tool is used by technical users since it is required to manipulate data via scripting. Furthermore, it can also be used by non-technical users.\nThere are no AI-enabled insights (Artificial Intelligence) or chart suggestions in QlikView. Additionally, Qlik Sense provides AI-enabled insights and chart suggestions.\nAdditionally, it enables us to integrate data from multiple sources and visualize those data. We can use it for data monitoring, security, application management, data auditing, data connectivity, and task management. QlikView  Qlik Sense QlikView  Qlik Sense QlikView Qlik Sense QlikView is a business intelligence tool that is widely used to provide analytical solutions, data visualization, and insight for business growth and monitoring. It is a version of QlikView, launched in 2014, with some advanced features. It helps in building interactive dashboards and reports and also extracting data from various data sources.\nWith QlikView, you can perform analytical operations on data through Online Analytical Processing (OLAP). There is no OLAP functionality in Qlik Sense.\nQlikView does not support self-service visualization. Data mining and analytics are not available either. Qlik Sense supports self-service visualization. Data mining and analytics are also included.\nIt does provide guided analytics functionality. It does not provide guided analytics functionality.\nQlikView provides basic visualizations. The attractive interface of Qlik Sense makes it a favourite among consumers. Therefore, Qlik Sense provides modern visualizations for representing data along with simple drag-and-drop functionality.\nThe tool is used by technical users since it is required to manipulate data via scripting. Furthermore, it can also be used by non-technical users.\nThere are no AI-enabled insights (Artificial Intelligence) or chart suggestions in QlikView. Additionally, Qlik Sense provides AI-enabled insights and chart suggestions.\nAdditionally, it enables us to integrate data from multiple sources and visualize those data. We can use it for data monitoring, security, application management, data auditing, data connectivity, and task management. QlikView is a business intelligence tool that is widely used to provide analytical solutions, data visualization, and insight for business growth and monitoring. It is a version of QlikView, launched in 2014, with some advanced features. It helps in building interactive dashboards and reports and also extracting data from various data sources. QlikView is a business intelligence tool that is widely used to provide analytical solutions, data visualization, and insight for business growth and monitoring. It is a version of QlikView, launched in 2014, with some advanced features. It helps in building interactive dashboards and reports and also extracting data from various data sources. With QlikView, you can perform analytical operations on data through Online Analytical Processing (OLAP). There is no OLAP functionality in Qlik Sense. With QlikView, you can perform analytical operations on data through Online Analytical Processing (OLAP). There is no OLAP functionality in Qlik Sense. QlikView does not support self-service visualization. Data mining and analytics are not available either. Qlik Sense supports self-service visualization. Data mining and analytics are also included. QlikView does not support self-service visualization. Data mining and analytics are not available either. Qlik Sense supports self-service visualization. Data mining and analytics are also included. It does provide guided analytics functionality. It does not provide guided analytics functionality. It does provide guided analytics functionality. It does not provide guided analytics functionality. QlikView provides basic visualizations. The attractive interface of Qlik Sense makes it a favourite among consumers. Therefore, Qlik Sense provides modern visualizations for representing data along with simple drag-and-drop functionality. QlikView provides basic visualizations. The attractive interface of Qlik Sense makes it a favourite among consumers. Therefore, Qlik Sense provides modern visualizations for representing data along with simple drag-and-drop functionality. The tool is used by technical users since it is required to manipulate data via scripting. Furthermore, it can also be used by non-technical users. The tool is used by technical users since it is required to manipulate data via scripting. Furthermore, it can also be used by non-technical users. There are no AI-enabled insights (Artificial Intelligence) or chart suggestions in QlikView. Additionally, Qlik Sense provides AI-enabled insights and chart suggestions. There are no AI-enabled insights (Artificial Intelligence) or chart suggestions in QlikView. Additionally, Qlik Sense provides AI-enabled insights and chart suggestions. Additionally, it enables us to integrate data from multiple sources and visualize those data. We can use it for data monitoring, security, application management, data auditing, data connectivity, and task management. Additionally, it enables us to integrate data from multiple sources and visualize those data. We can use it for data monitoring, security, application management, data auditing, data connectivity, and task management.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. What are QlikView Server and QlikView Publisher?",
        "answer": "QlikView Server: Basically, QlikView Server makes QlikView documents available to connected clients. In addition to nesting multiple servers for data load balancing, the QlikView Server enables users to access data both on a PC and on their mobile phones.\nQlikView Publisher: QlikView Publisher handles data management, data access, data reduction, and distribution. In addition to ensuring that the right information reaches the right user at the right time, QlikView Publisher facilitates centralized administration and management. QlikView Server: Basically, QlikView Server makes QlikView documents available to connected clients. In addition to nesting multiple servers for data load balancing, the QlikView Server enables users to access data both on a PC and on their mobile phones. QlikView Server QlikView Publisher: QlikView Publisher handles data management, data access, data reduction, and distribution. In addition to ensuring that the right information reaches the right user at the right time, QlikView Publisher facilitates centralized administration and management. QlikView Publisher",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. State the difference between join and keep.",
        "answer": "The differences between the keep and join commands are as follows: Join Keep\nThis command will join two tables and merge them into one. Using this command, we can implement join logic on two tables while also maintaining two tables separately in the memory. \nA concept of an outer join is available. The concept of an outer keep does not exist. Join Keep\nThis command will join two tables and merge them into one. Using this command, we can implement join logic on two tables while also maintaining two tables separately in the memory. \nA concept of an outer join is available. The concept of an outer keep does not exist. Join Keep Join Keep Join Keep This command will join two tables and merge them into one. Using this command, we can implement join logic on two tables while also maintaining two tables separately in the memory. \nA concept of an outer join is available. The concept of an outer keep does not exist. This command will join two tables and merge them into one. Using this command, we can implement join logic on two tables while also maintaining two tables separately in the memory. This command will join two tables and merge them into one. Using this command, we can implement join logic on two tables while also maintaining two tables separately in the memory. A concept of an outer join is available. The concept of an outer keep does not exist. A concept of an outer join is available. The concept of an outer keep does not exist.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. Explain QVW and QVD in QlikView.",
        "answer": "QVD: QVD stands for Qlikview data. In the QVD data file, raw data is stored so that it can be later used for the Data Model. Data is stored in compressed form. \nQVW: QVW stands for Qlikview application. A QVW file contains objects, charts, reports, and a data model. It is used to display data in charts and reports. QVD: QVD stands for Qlikview data. In the QVD data file, raw data is stored so that it can be later used for the Data Model. Data is stored in compressed form. QVD: Qlikview data QVW: QVW stands for Qlikview application. A QVW file contains objects, charts, reports, and a data model. It is used to display data in charts and reports. QVW: Qlikview application",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What are synthetic keys?",
        "answer": "The composite key relationship occurs when two or more internal tables have some fields in common. To handle this, QlikView automatically creates synthetic keys. Synthetic keys are fields that represent all possible combinations of composite keys. Synthetic keys are often indicative of an incorrect data model, but that is not always the case. If, however, you have synthetic keys that are based on other synthetic keys, this is a sure indication that your data model is incorrect.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. State difference between match and pick in QlikView.",
        "answer": "1. Match(): It compares the first parameter to all the following parameters and returns the total number of expressions that match. It is case-sensitive. 1. Match(): Syntax: Syntax: match( str, expr1 [ , expr2,...exprN ]) match( str, expr1 [ , expr2,...exprN ]) Example: Example: match( M, 'Apr','May','Jun') match( M, 'Apr','May','Jun') Here, \nIf M=Apr, it will return 1.  If M=Jang, it will return 0. 2. Pick(): This is a QlikView script function. Pick() works the same way as Excel's INDEX() function. It returns the nth expression in the list. 2. Pick() Syntax: Syntax: pick(n, expr1[ , expr2,...exprN]) pick(n, expr1[ , expr2,...exprN]) Example: Example: pick( N, 'A','B',4, 6 ) pick( N, 'A','B',4, 6 ) Here, If N = 2, it will return 'B'. If N = 3, it will return 4.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. State difference between Information Density and Subset Ratio in QlikView.",
        "answer": "Information Density: It shows the percentage of rows containing a distinct value for a particular field.\nSubset Ratio: It is a measure of the percentage of each distinct value of a particular field in the table as compared to all distinct values of the same field in the entire data model. Information Density: It shows the percentage of rows containing a distinct value for a particular field. Information Density Subset Ratio: It is a measure of the percentage of each distinct value of a particular field in the table as compared to all distinct values of the same field in the entire data model. Subset Ratio",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What do you mean by the Kurtosis() and Skew() functions?",
        "answer": "Both Kurtosis() and Skew() are types of statistical aggregate functions. Kurtosis(): This function measures the peak of a distribution curve. A leptokurtic distribution (Kurtosis > 3) has a tall and thin curve. A leptokurtic distribution has values close to the mean or at its extrema. Platykurtic distributions (Kurtosis < 3) have moderately spread out values. Mesokurtic (Kurtosis=3) distributions are defined as distributions whose shape lies between the leptokurtic distribution and the platykurtic distribution. Kurtosis():   Skew(): This function measures the asymmetry of a distribution curve. A zero value of skewness causes the distribution curve to split into two equal halves at the median. Negative values of the skewness cause the distribution to have a longer tail towards the left side of the curve. Positive values of the skewness cause the distribution to have a longer tail towards the right side of the curve. Skew():  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What do you mean by match and interval match in QlikView?",
        "answer": "Among Qlikview's unique features are IntervalMatch and Match Functions. Both of those functions are extremely helpful in industrial setups or anywhere where data records change frequently. Match(): QlikView's Match Function lets you match a string value expression to the associated data in the table columns. By applying the match function and mentioning the expression you are looking for, you will get the entire data in the table related to that expression.\nIntervalMatch(): QlikView offers the IntervalMatch function as a way of matching numeric values in one table with intervals or durations in another table. The numerical values may be data, timestamps, scores, etc. Match(): QlikView's Match Function lets you match a string value expression to the associated data in the table columns. By applying the match function and mentioning the expression you are looking for, you will get the entire data in the table related to that expression. Match() IntervalMatch(): QlikView offers the IntervalMatch function as a way of matching numeric values in one table with intervals or durations in another table. The numerical values may be data, timestamps, scores, etc. IntervalMatch()",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. State difference between list box and multi-box.",
        "answer": "List Box: Using a list box, you can choose a single field from a table that has been loaded into QlikView memory. As a result, you will see a single list of values for the field you have selected.  When a value is selected in the list box, the related values in the other sheet objects are highlighted. There is also a search feature, which allows you to find specific values within a list box. This is very useful when you have a very long list of values.\nMulti-Box: This type of box displays all the values from multiple fields as drop-down values. This is a compressed table box that displays only the field names in the columns and allows you to view all values of a particular field by using a drop-down menu. This box allows you to save a lot of space on your dashboard or sheet while adding more objects to the dashboard for better analytics. When a value is selected in the list box, the related values in the other sheet objects are highlighted. This speeds up visually analyzing a sheet. Additionally, you can follow drill-down paths among various sheet objects. List Box: Using a list box, you can choose a single field from a table that has been loaded into QlikView memory. As a result, you will see a single list of values for the field you have selected.  When a value is selected in the list box, the related values in the other sheet objects are highlighted. There is also a search feature, which allows you to find specific values within a list box. This is very useful when you have a very long list of values. List Box Multi-Box: This type of box displays all the values from multiple fields as drop-down values. This is a compressed table box that displays only the field names in the columns and allows you to view all values of a particular field by using a drop-down menu. This box allows you to save a lot of space on your dashboard or sheet while adding more objects to the dashboard for better analytics. When a value is selected in the list box, the related values in the other sheet objects are highlighted. This speeds up visually analyzing a sheet. Additionally, you can follow drill-down paths among various sheet objects. Multi-Box",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. Explain what a join is and write its types.",
        "answer": "The join command in QlikView makes it possible to combine data from two separate data sets into a single set. A join in QlikView is similar to a join in SQL. When the output is generated, only columns and rows whose values match the join conditions are displayed. There are three types of joins as follows: Inner Join: With this join, only the rows present in both tables (left and right) are merged and displayed as a single table.\nOuter Join: With this join, all the rows present in both tables (left and right) are merged into and displayed as a single table.\nLeft Join: This involves retrieving all the rows from the left table and only the rows matching from the right table.\nRight Join: This involves retrieving all the rows from the right table and only the rows matching from the left table. Inner Join: With this join, only the rows present in both tables (left and right) are merged and displayed as a single table. Inner Join: Outer Join: With this join, all the rows present in both tables (left and right) are merged into and displayed as a single table. Outer Join: Left Join: This involves retrieving all the rows from the left table and only the rows matching from the right table. Left Join: Right Join: This involves retrieving all the rows from the right table and only the rows matching from the left table. Right Join:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. Explain CAL (Client Access License) and write its types.",
        "answer": "To access or open a QlikView document from a QlikView Server (QVS), each client/user requires its own license. A Client Access License (CAL) enables access to QlikView documents residing on a QlikView Server. For CALs, you need a QlikView Publisher license. The following types of CALs are available in QlikView: Named User CAL: With Named User CAL, a single named user can have access to all QlikView documents on the QlikView Server for as long as required. Named user CALs are specific to the machine or the user. While this license cannot be shared, it allows users to access any number of documents for an unlimited amount of time.\nDocument CAL: With Document CAL, a single named user can access only a single QlikView document on the QlikView Server at any time. A single user can be assigned multiple Document CALs. \nSession CAL: In a scenario where there are a great number of non-frequent users, session CALs are used. With the Session CAL, a single named or anonymous user has access to all the QlikView documents on the QlikView server. Sessions CALs comprise a pool of licenses that are assigned automatically to users or clients based on the first-come, first-served.\nUsage CAL: With the Usage CAL, a single named or anonymous user has access to a single QlikView document on the QlikView server for 60 minutes every 28 days. Usage CALs comprise a pool of licenses that are assigned automatically to users or clients based on the first-come, first-served. Named User CAL: With Named User CAL, a single named user can have access to all QlikView documents on the QlikView Server for as long as required. Named user CALs are specific to the machine or the user. While this license cannot be shared, it allows users to access any number of documents for an unlimited amount of time. Named User CAL Document CAL: With Document CAL, a single named user can access only a single QlikView document on the QlikView Server at any time. A single user can be assigned multiple Document CALs. Document CAL Session CAL: In a scenario where there are a great number of non-frequent users, session CALs are used. With the Session CAL, a single named or anonymous user has access to all the QlikView documents on the QlikView server. Sessions CALs comprise a pool of licenses that are assigned automatically to users or clients based on the first-come, first-served. Session CAL Usage CAL: With the Usage CAL, a single named or anonymous user has access to a single QlikView document on the QlikView server for 60 minutes every 28 days. Usage CALs comprise a pool of licenses that are assigned automatically to users or clients based on the first-come, first-served. Usage CAL",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. What are the various services offered by the QlikView Server environment?",
        "answer": "When a QlikView Server is run with a QVP (QlikView Publisher) license, the following services are available: QMS (QlikView Management Service)\nQVWS QlikView (Web Server) \nQVS (QlikView Server)\nQlik License Service\nDSC (QlikView Directory Service Connector)\nQDS (QlikView Distribution Service) QMS (QlikView Management Service) QVWS QlikView (Web Server) QVS (QlikView Server) Qlik License Service DSC (QlikView Directory Service Connector) QDS (QlikView Distribution Service) When QlikView Server is run without a QVP (QlikView Publisher) license, the following services are available: QMS (QlikView Management Service)\nQVWS QlikView (Web Server) \nQVS (QlikView Server)\nQlik License Service\nQlikView ReloadEngine (not a service)\nDSC (QlikView Directory Service Connector) QMS (QlikView Management Service) QVWS QlikView (Web Server) QVS (QlikView Server) Qlik License Service QlikView ReloadEngine (not a service) DSC (QlikView Directory Service Connector)",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. In QlikView Management Console, what do you mean by tasks and triggers?",
        "answer": "Tasks: Tasks are used to perform a range of different operations, and they are handled by the QSS (Qlik Sense Scheduler Service). Tasks are generally created for reloading data and distributing dashboards to users.\nTriggers: A task is executed by a trigger or manually from the task overview page.  Triggers are used to schedule a task to be performed at a specific time. Additional triggers can be created to execute the task. Tasks: Tasks are used to perform a range of different operations, and they are handled by the QSS (Qlik Sense Scheduler Service). Tasks are generally created for reloading data and distributing dashboards to users. Tasks: Triggers: A task is executed by a trigger or manually from the task overview page.  Triggers are used to schedule a task to be performed at a specific time. Additional triggers can be created to execute the task. Triggers:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. In QlikView, what types of tables are there?",
        "answer": "Tables are the most common way of presenting data. Tables in QlikView can be categorized into four types: pivot tables, crosstables, straight tables, and mapping tables. All of these types of QlikView tables display data uniquely. Pivot table: Table pivots are commonly used to show the sum of values across several dimensions in a table. It can be used in data analysis. You can create pivot tables using chart objects.\nStraight table: Straight tables are the most basic form of data representation in QlikView. Simple yet powerful, these tables allow you to rearrange columns, sort them, and colour the background.\nCrosstable: Cross tables are tables where the columns and rows swap or switch places. The row’s values repeat themselves for every column value in a cross table. You can create a cross table in the File Wizard.\nMapping table: This table maps the column values of two tables. Alternatively, it is referred to as a lookup table, which is only used to locate a related value in another table. A mapping table is temporarily created in memory and is automatically dropped after script execution is complete. Pivot table: Table pivots are commonly used to show the sum of values across several dimensions in a table. It can be used in data analysis. You can create pivot tables using chart objects. Pivot table: Straight table: Straight tables are the most basic form of data representation in QlikView. Simple yet powerful, these tables allow you to rearrange columns, sort them, and colour the background. Straight table: Crosstable: Cross tables are tables where the columns and rows swap or switch places. The row’s values repeat themselves for every column value in a cross table. You can create a cross table in the File Wizard. Crosstable: Mapping table: This table maps the column values of two tables. Alternatively, it is referred to as a lookup table, which is only used to locate a related value in another table. A mapping table is temporarily created in memory and is automatically dropped after script execution is complete. Mapping table:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. What are the different types of charts used in QlikView?",
        "answer": "There are various types of charts available in QlikView. Some of them are as follows: Bar chart: It shows numerical data values as blocks of varying sizes. Bar charts display categories on the x-axis and the corresponding calculated values on the y-axis, such as sums, counts, and averages.\nLine chart: Line charts connect numerical values to present information. A line chart presents information using a series of data points with a continuous line.\nCombo chart: This type of chart combines bar charts and line charts. There will be two measures displayed in a category, one by a line and one by a bar.\nFunnel chart: A graphic showing the progression of a process or a flow of data. \nBlock Chart: The block chart shows a relationship between measure values as blocks. The area of each block depends on the measured value.\nMekko chart: Mekko charts are like bar charts but with varying widths. The data is represented by bars of different sizes and widths.\nGauge chart: The gauge chart shows the value of a single expression without any dimensions.  Gauge charts are used to measure various aspects of a business, such as the profit earned, total quantity sold, etc., using gauge meters.  By setting the maximum & minimum range of gauge meters, you can assess your performances accordingly. Bar chart: It shows numerical data values as blocks of varying sizes. Bar charts display categories on the x-axis and the corresponding calculated values on the y-axis, such as sums, counts, and averages. Bar chart: Line chart: Line charts connect numerical values to present information. A line chart presents information using a series of data points with a continuous line. Line chart: Combo chart: This type of chart combines bar charts and line charts. There will be two measures displayed in a category, one by a line and one by a bar. Combo chart Funnel chart: A graphic showing the progression of a process or a flow of data. Funnel chart: Block Chart: The block chart shows a relationship between measure values as blocks. The area of each block depends on the measured value. Block Chart: Mekko chart: Mekko charts are like bar charts but with varying widths. The data is represented by bars of different sizes and widths. Mekko chart: Gauge chart: The gauge chart shows the value of a single expression without any dimensions.  Gauge charts are used to measure various aspects of a business, such as the profit earned, total quantity sold, etc., using gauge meters.  By setting the maximum & minimum range of gauge meters, you can assess your performances accordingly. Gauge chart:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. What is a QlikView object that does not have a dimension but only has an expression?",
        "answer": "QlikView objects that do not have a dimension but only have an expression are gauge charts. A gauge chart shows the value of a single expression without any dimensions. Here are some examples of gauge charts:  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    },
    {
        "question": "17. Define the trellis chart in QlikView.",
        "answer": "Trellis charts are composed of small charts (also called small multiples). It is a repetition of a chart across a grid and this grid is typically determined by the number of dimension values. A trellis chart can be used to compare metrics for different groups of data. It is included in the Visualization bundle. Example: Below is an example of a trellis chart based on bar charts of sales data for different product categories like babywear, bath clothes, children’s wear, and so on.   Conclusion In terms of business intelligence and data visualization, QlikView is one of the most popular and fastest-growing tools in the marketplace. In essence, QlikView is a powerful data visualization tool similar to Tableau that integrates analytics and statistics to provide a more unified view of data to help analysts and managers make informed decisions using data. The growing demand for QlikView has led companies to actively hire QlikView professionals for various roles, such as QlikView developer, Qlik Sense developer, BI analyst, QlikView application developer, Qlik Sense administrator, etc. In this article, we have compiled a list of top Interview Questions that are quick and insightful, and which provide ample information essential to the interview process. Hopefully, we have cleared up any lingering doubts or questions you may have had. Good luck with your future endeavours. Additional Interview Preparation Resources Additional Interview Preparation Resources Power BI Interview Questions\nData Analyst Interview Questions\nTableau Interview Questions\nTechnical Interview Questions\nCoding Interview Questions\nData Structures and Algorithms\nMock Interview\nInterviewBit Blog Power BI Interview Questions Power BI Interview Questions Data Analyst Interview Questions Data Analyst Interview Questions Tableau Interview Questions Tableau Interview Questions Technical Interview Questions Technical Interview Questions Technical Interview Questions Coding Interview Questions Coding Interview Questions Data Structures and Algorithms Data Structures and Algorithms Mock Interview Mock Interview InterviewBit Blog InterviewBit Blog",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "qlikview"
    }
]